Bin Feng

Software Engineer at Google

Summary

Trustworthy, Optimistic, Determined.

Relentless commitment to innovation. Have the courage to dream the impossible, and make it the truth.

Passionate in Technology and Product.

Expertise in Back-end, Big Data Streaming and Batching, Cloud Computing.

Interest in Team Lead or Engineering Manager position.

Feel free to reach me through Linkedin InBox Mail or Email (hello.bin.feng@gmail.com).

########

I ask these questions to myself every day:

How far can you see?

How big can you think?

And most importantly, how far will you go for yourself?

Experience

Software Engineer at Google

February 2016 - Present

G is for Google!

Google's mission is to organize the world's information and make it universally accessible and useful.

Google is not a conventional company. We do not intend to become one.

I am working on distributed big data processing and analyzing.

Software Engineer at Salesforce

January 2015 - February 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Salesforce's mission is to build the customer success platform.

I built up distributed data processing (batch and streaming) pipelines from scratch.

Teaching Assistant in Cloud Computing at Carnegie Mellon University

May 2014 - December 2014 (8 months)

Teaching Assistant for course 15619 Cloud Computing, School of Computer Science, CMU http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~msakr/15619-f14/index.html

Backend Developer Intern at PayPal

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

Backend Development

Tech Stack: Node.js, Python, Hadoop, Hive, Pig, MongoDB, ZeroMQ, Storm

Researcher

September 2009 - August 2013 (4 years)

Developed AI software for a team of robots playing soccer. (RoboCup SSL)

Software Developer at Devatus Oy

January 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 6 months)

Backend software development

Software Developer Intern at Arena Interactive

May 2010 - December 2010 (8 months)

Backend software development

Education

Carnegie Mellon University

Master of Science (M.S.), Information Technology, 2013 - 2015

Honors and Awards

Carnegie Mellon University Information Networking Institute Scholarship

Bin Feng

Software Engineer at Google



Contact Bin on LinkedIn